Thomas Wood Stevens papers, 1895-1984 (bulk 1897-1937)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Thomas Wood Stevens papers, 1895-1984 (bulk 1897-1937)
MS 002
The collection contains biographical materials such as early notebooks of writings and sketches, articles about Stevens, and family photographs.
Stevens, Thomas Wood, 1880-1942
36 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Biographical Note
Thomas Wood Stevens was an artist, teacher, author, and theater director. He served has head of the Illustration Department at the Art Institute of Chicago from 1903-1911; he was cofounder of Blue Sky Press, 1899-1907; he served as head of the Drama Department at the Carnegie Institute of Technology, 1913-1925; then at the Kenneth Sawyer Goodman Memorial Theatre, 1925- 1930; he was the director of various university and community theaters, and of the Globe Theatre Shakespearean productions performed at several American expositions and centennials; finally he was in charge of the Drama Department at the University of Arizona from 1941-1942.
Organization
This collection is organized into seven series:
Series I: Biographical Materials, 1895-1951
Series II: Correspondence, 1899-1942
Series III: Blue Sky Press, Art Institute of Chicago, University of Wisconsin and Carnegie Institute of Technology Materials, 1899-1949
Series IV: Theater Materials, 1901-1979
Series V: Pageants, 1900-1941
Series VI: Published Works and Manuscripts, 1896-1984
Series VII: Etchings, no dates
Scope and Content Note
The collection contains biographical materials such as early notebooks of writings and sketches, articles about Stevens, and family photographs. Manuscripts by Stevens include pageants, poems, plays, articles, stories, and an original draft and illustrations for his book, The Theatre from Athens to Broadway. Major correspondents are Kenneth Goodman, Samuel Hume, Alden Noble, Ben Payne, Frederick Goudy, and Bertha Jacques. Stevens' work as a theater director is represented by programs, clippings, scrapbooks, prompt books, Shakespearean texts, and photographs of performances; as well as blueprints of Goodman Memorial Theatre and Globe Theatre, Chicago. Included in the collection are Blue Sky Press publications, some written by Stevens; 65 other books by private presses; and seven little magazines. Original etchings by Stevens include a series on American universities.
Stevens, Thomas Wood, 1880-1942 -- Archives; Goodman, Kenneth Sawyer, 1883-1918 -- Correspondence; Hume, Samuel J. (Samuel James), 1885-1948 -- Correspondence; Noble, Alden Charles, b. 1880- -- Correspondence; Payne, Ben Iden, 1881-1976 -- Correspondence; Jacques, Bertha -- Correspondence; Goudy, Frederic W. (Frederic William), 1865-1947 -- Correspondence; Globe Theatre Productions -- History -- Sources; Blue Sky Press; Carnegie Institute of Technology -- History -- Sources; Art Institute of Chicago. Kenneth Sawyer Goodman Memorial Theatre -- History -- Sources; Chicago Society of Etchers; Theaters -- Designs and plans; Small press books -- Specimens; Small presses -- United States; Theater -- United States -- History -- 20th century; College theater -- United States -- History; Promptbooks -- Specimens; Pageants -- United States -- History -- Sources; Little magazines -- United States -- Specimens; Theatrical producers and directors -- United States; Etching, American; Correspondence; Etchings; Manuscripts; Photographs
Separated Material
Scrapbooks received with the collection can be found in the University of Arizona Special Collections Theater Program Files
Container List
- Series I: Biographical Materials, 1895-1951
  - Thomas Wood Stevens Calendar (Compiled by Mrs. Stevens). 1840-1942 (Box 1)
  - Personal Clippings (Scrapbook compiled by Special Collections). 1902-1947 (Box 1)
  - Educational Theater Journal. December 1951 (Box 1)
    "Thomas Wood Stevens: A Memorial Issue." (2 copies).
  - Lorado Taft's Indian Statue "Black Hawk." (Box 1)
    An account of the unveiling ceremonies at Eagles' Nest Bluff, Oregon, (Illustration), July 1, 1911. Limited edition of 50 copies; this is copy no. 11. Signed etching by Thomas Wood Stevens.
  - Miscellaneous personal material. (Box 1, Folder 1-3)
  - Wartime service and activities., 1918 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Periodicals containing references to Thomas Wood Stevens. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Dedication of the Thomas Wood Stevens Collection, University of Arizona., 1950 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Stevens Collection books elsewhere in the library. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Lists of gifts from friends and associates and volumes from the personal library of Thomas Wood Stevens.
  - Diaries., 1901, 1920-1921, 1923-1924, 1929 (summer), 1931, 1935 (Box 1a)
  - Miscellaneous sketches, drawings, etc., including six notebooks. (Box 1a)
  - Miscellaneous commemorative medallions, tokens, foreign coins. (Box 1a)
  - Thomas Wood Stevens' copy of a "Text Book of Free Hand Drawing", by F. T. Daniels, Boston: D. C. Heath & Co., 1895 (Box 1a)
  - Album of personal photographs compiled by Mrs. Stevens. (Box 2)
    Also includes an envelope of thirteen additional photographs taken in 1940.
  - The Index: Pittsburgh's Illustrated and Society Weekly., May 18, 1918 (Box 2)
    Photo of Thomas Wood Stevens is on the cover; biographical sketch, page four, article on Joan of Arc Pageant, page nine.
  - Poster: "The Blue Sky," a montlhy magazine, price $0.20 (3 copies). (Box 2)
  - Poster: "University of Wisconsin." Two lectures by Thomas Wood Stevens: "The Making of a Pageant" and "The Pageant of the Italian Renaissance." March 27, 1912 or 1913 (Box 2)
  - "The Summer Man: His Wanderings". Being lasting record of a stunt by Thomas Wood Stevens and Frank B. Rae, Jr. (Box 2)
  - Resolution adopted by the faculties of the University of Arizona on the death of Thomas Wood Stevens. March 5, 1942 (Box 2)
  - Music scores, words by Thomas Wood Stevens. (Box 2)
    Gerald Tyler: "Rejoice, O Hills." (2 copies)
    Haniel Long: "Missouri."
    Olaf Andersen: "The Corn Chant." (2 copies)
    Olaf Andersen: "Chorus of Pioneers."
  - L'Album Des Poilus de A. Barrere, souvenirs de guerre, Paris. 1914-1919 (Box 2)
- Series II: Correspondence, 1899-1942
  - Family. 1913-1942 (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
  - Cowley, Frederick Kitson. 1912-1927 (Box 3, Folder 3-4)
  - Dickinson, Thomas H. 1913-1921 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Emerson, Alfred and Edith. 1913-1934 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Flavin, Martin. 1923-1940 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Gage, Harry L. 1909-1927 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Goodman, Kenneth Sawyer. 1910-1919 (Box 3, Folder 9-10)
  - Green, Paul. 1929-1930 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Hume, Samuel J. 1914-1941 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Kane, Whitford. 1918-1940 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Kich, Frederick H. 1915-1940 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Langdon, William Chauncy. 1910-1920 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Long, Haniel. 1913-1938 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Mabie, Edward C. 1919-1941 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - McConnell, Frederic C. 1914-1941 (Box 4, Folder 6-7)
  - Macgowan, Kenneth. 1919-1941 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Mackaye, Percy. 1913-1933 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Mansfield, Beatrice (Mrs. Richard Mansfield). 1917-1934 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Moody, Harriet (Mrs. William Vaughn Moody). 1923-1932 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Moses, Montrose, J. 1914-1921 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Noble, Alden. 1910-1918 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Oglebay, Kate. 1917-1925 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Payne, B. Iden. 1914-1940 (Box 5, Folder 1-3)
  - Poel, William. 1916-1918 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Rice, Cale Young. 1917-1918 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Rice, Wallace. 1902-1925 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Robertson, Donald. 1909-1923 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Seymour, Ralph Fletcher. 1899?-1918 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Smith, Joseph Lindon. 1914-1932 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Smith, Luther Ely. 1915-1933 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Townsend, Harry. 1909-1939 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Wescott, Glenway. 1920 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Drama League of America. 1911-1919 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Little Theatre Society of Indiana. 1914-1920 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Art: miscellaneous correspondence. 1903-1930 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Art: H. W. Buemming, Architect (various murals by Thomas Wood Stevens). 1910-1915 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Art: Frank Brangwyn (includes 2 photographs). 1913-1914 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Art: Marc T. Nielson. (See also Globe Theater Files). 1930-1941 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Etching: miscellaneous correspondence. 1908-1922 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Etching: Bertha Jacques and the Chicago Society of Etchers. 1912-1919 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Etching: Brown-Robertson Company. 1911-1924 (Box 6, Folder 7-8)
  - Etching: Frank Crowninshield. 1911-1913 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Fine Arts Shop of Chicago. 1913-1915 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Panama-Pacific International Exposition, San Francisco. 1915 (Box 6, Folder 11-12)
  - Publishers: D. Appleton and Company. 1907, 1924-1941 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    Nursery Maid of Heaven, The Theatre of Athens to Broadway, and plays by Kenneth Sawyer Goodman.
  - Publishers: C. C. Birchard. 1918-1922 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    Drawing of the Sword, Joan of Arc, Pageant of Victory and Peace.
  - Publishers: Dramatists Play Service. 1938-1941 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    Drum Head, Tour du Monde, Knights of Terror.
  - Publishers: Samuel French. 1930-1942 (Box 7, Folder 4-5)
    Includes Joan of Arc, Globe versions of Shakespeare, Drum Head, Tour du Monde, Venus and Adolphus, Camille in Roaring Camp, Knights of Terror.
  - Publishers: Henry Holt and Company. 1915-1926 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    Includes Ryland, Holbein in Blackfriars, Goya, Don Juan, Joan of Arc.
  - Publishers: Midland Company. 1908-1910 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Publishers: Prang Company (Edwin O. Grover). 1910-1938 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Publishers: American Crayon Company. 1941 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Publishers: Frank Shay. 1920-1925 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    Three Wishes, Fifty One-act Plays, Poe.
  - Publishers: Stage Guild. 1912-1938 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    Daimio's Head, Holbein in Blackfriars, Masque of Montezuma, Ryland, Chaplet of Pan, Pageant for Independence Day, Drawing of the Sword, Rainald and the Wolf, plays by Kenneth Sawyer.
  - Publishers: Donald C. Vaughan, Laurence J. Gomme, and the Little Book Shop Around the Corner. 1914-1919 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    Dust of the Road, Masques of East and West.
  - Poetry: A Magazine of Verse (Harriet Monroe). 1912-1914 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Poetry: A Magazine of Verse (George Dillon). 1940 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Theatre Arts Monthly. 1931-1940 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Publishers: miscellaneous correspondence about stories, articles, etc. 1901-1942 (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
  - Publishers: various, regarding Westward Under Vega. 1937-1940 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Publishers: various, regarding mystery books by Thomas Wood Stevens' daughter. 1937-1938 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Agent: Hewitt H. Howland. 1937-1940 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Series III: Blue Sky Press, Art Institute of Chicago, University of Wisconsin and Carnegie Institute of Technology Materials, 1899-1949
  - Correspondence: Blue Sky Press. 1899-1902 (Box 9, Folder 1-3)
    Includes correspondence with Frank B. Rae, Jr., Frank Walter Allen, and Charlotte Becker.
  - Correspondence: Blue Sky Press and Art Institute of Chicago. 1903-1905 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    Includes correspondence with F. W. Goudy and Bruce Rogers.
  - Correspondence: Art Institute of Chicago. 1906-1914 (Box 9, Folder 5-6)
    Includes correspondence with F. W. Goudy, Bruce Rogers, and Howard Pyle.
  - Correspondence: Art Institute of Chicago (Murals by Students). 1910-1914 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: University of Wisconsin (Lectures, etc.). 1912-1913 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - The Spanish Main. Art Institute of Chicago. 1905 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    By Alden C. Noble and Thomas Wood Stevens. Includes program photos, letters from Harrison Grey Fiske and Otis Skinner.
  - The Topaz Amulet. Art Institute of Chicago. 1906-1907 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    By Wallace Rice and Thomas Wood Stevens. Includes program, photos, clippings and notes.
  - Cellini of Florence. Chicago Art Students League. 1906, 1910 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    By Thomas Wood Stevens. Includes programs, photos and clippings.
  - Various productions of the Chicago Art Students League. (Programs, clippings, etc.). 1906-1914 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Chicago Theatre Society. (Programs, correspondence, etc.). 1911-1913 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Cliff Dwellers. (Programs, correspondence, etc.). 1909-1915 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    Includes the Cliff Dwellers Yearbook for 1911, containing The Masque of Quetzal's Bowl by Thomas Wood Stevens and Kenneth Sawyer Goodman
  - Donald Robertson Players, Chicago. (Programs, clippings, etc.). 1908-1913 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Noble, Alden Charles: The Fall of Granada. (Program, typescript). 1910 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Noble, Alden Charles: Murder as a Fine Art. (Typescript). (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Lecture notes: Art Institute of Chicago and University of Wisconsin. (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Art Institute of Chicago: Circular of Instruction for 1907-1908. 1907-1908 (Box 10)
  - Art Institute of Chicago: The Book and Catalog of the Second Retrospective Exhibition of the Art Institute Alumni Association. 1922 (Box 10)
    Contains "The Manuscript on Gray Charcoal Paper; note regarding manuscript," by Thomas Wood Stevens.
  - Scrapbook of clippings regarding The Faith Healer as produced in New York and Cambridge, Massachusetts. 1909-1910 (Box 10)
  - Carnegie Institute of Technology: Correspondence. 1913-1917 (Box 11, Folder 1-8)
    Includes letters from Padraic Colum, October 23, 1914 and Gordon Craig, February 6, 1915
  - Carnegie Institute of Technology: Carnegie Tech Pageants and Special Programs. (Typescripts and notes). 1915-1920 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Carnegie Institute of Technology: Correspondence. 1918 (Box 12, Folder 1-5)
  - Carnegie Institute of Technology: YMCA National War Work Council. 1918-1919 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Carnegie Institute of Technology: 14th Annual Report of the Director. For the year ending March 31, 1917. 1917 (Box 12)
  - Carnegie Institute of Technology: Bulletin, Division of the Arts. 1918-1919 (Box 12)
  - Carnegie Institute of Technology: Theatre Arts Magazine. (Carnegie Tech library copy). January 1919 (Box 12)
  - Carnegie Institute of Technology: Carnegie Tech War Verse. 1918 (Box 12)
  - Carnegie Institute of Technology: The Soldier's Progress; from the war letters of Carnegie Tech men. 1918 (Box 12)
  - Carnegie Institute of Technology: Correspondence. 1920-1924 (Box 13)
  - Carnegie Institute of Technology: 18th Annual Report of the President. April 1, 1920-June 30, 1921 (Box 13)
  - Carnegie Institute of Technology: Bulletin, Division of the Arts. 1920-1921 (Box 13)
  - Carnegie Institute of Technology: Bulletin, College of Fine Arts. 1922-1923 (Box 13)
  - Carnegie Institute of Technology: Programs. 1914-1924 (Box 14, Folder 1-9)
  - Carnegie Institute of Technology: Miscellaneous items (History, memorabilia, etc.). (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Carnegie Institute of Technology: Album of clippings. 1914-1949 (Box 14)
  - Carnegie Institute of Technology: Photographs. (Box 15, Folder 1-53)
  - Carnegie Institute of Technology: Album of photographs compiled by John A. Willard, student. (Box 15)
  - Carnegie Institute of Technology Drama Compositions: Beyer, William (Student), Furrowed Earth. (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Carnegie Institute of Technology Drama Compositions: Beyer,Beyer, WilliamWilliam (Student), Underlings. (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Carnegie Institute of Technology Drama Compositions: Beyer, William (Student), Wings. (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Carnegie Institute of Technology Drama Compositions: Day, Frank P. and O'Brien, J. Vick (faculty), Roses of Mercatel. (John A. Willard's prompt copy). (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Carnegie Institute of Technology Drama Compositions: Floyd, Sara Trainor (student), An Annotated Bibliography of Plays for Outdoor Theatres. M. A. Thesis, Depart of Drama. 1923 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Carnegie Institute of Technology Drama Compositions: Hamilton, Harry (student), Renny's Place. (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Carnegie Institute of Technology Drama Compositions: Hamilton, Harry (student), You're Next. (Box 16, Folder 7)
    Accompanied by a letter from Harry Hamilton to Mrs. Thomas Wood Stevens, July 20, 1943.
  - Carnegie Institute of Technology Drama Compositions: Osborne, Hubert and Byre, Laurence (faculty), Life and Death of William Shakespeare. (John A Willard's prompt copy). (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Carnegie Institute of Technology Drama Compositions: Parker, Louis (student), The Minuet. (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Carnegie Institute of Technology Drama Compositions: Stehli, Edgar (student), The Gate. (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Carnegie Institute of Technology Drama Compositions: Anon, Sweeney. (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Carnegie Institute of Technology: Scrapbook compiled by John A Willard, student. 1919-1923 (Box 17)
- Series IV: Theater Materials, 1901-1979
  - Goodman Memorial Theatre Correspondence: prospectus, publicity. (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Goodman Memorial Theatre Correspondence. 1923-1930 (Box 18, Folder 2-6)
  - Goodman Memorial Theatre Correspondence: resignation 1930 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Goodman Memorial Theatre Correspondence: financial matters. (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Goodman Memorial Theatre Correspondence: staff, students (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Goodman Memorial Theatre: 21 folders of photographs. (Box 19)
  - Goodman Memorial Theatre: programs. 1924-1930 (Box 19, Folder 1-8)
  - Goodman Memorial Theatre: miscellaneous items (history, memorabilia, articles). (Box 19, Folder 9-10)
  - Goodman Memorial Theatre: album of clippings. 1924-1930 (Box 20)
  - Goodman Memorial Theatre: blueprints. (Box 20)
  - Goodman Memorial Theatre: correspondence regarding architectural plans. 1922-1925 (Box 20)
- Series II: Correspondence (continued), 1899-1942
  - General. 1930-1934 (Box 21, Folder 1-5)
  - Little Theatre of St. Louis. (See also Box 27 for programs, clippings, photographs). 1931-1933 (Box 21, Folder 6-8)
  - University of Michigan Summer Session. (See also Box 28 for programs, clippings, photographs). 1931-1933 (Box 21, Folder 9-11)
  - National Theatre Conference. 1932-1934 (Box 21, Folder 12-14)
  - Bonstelle Civic Theatre, Detroit. (See also Box 28 for programs, clippings, photographs). 1933-1934 (Box 21, Folder 15-16)
- Series IV: Theater Materials (continued), 1901-1979
  - Globe Theatre correspondence. 1934-1942 (Box 22, Folder 1-7)
    Includes letter from Don Marquis, July 29, 1935.
  - Globe Theatre: blueprints. Century of Progress. 1934 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Globe Theatre: photographs of Chicago. 1934 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Globe Theatre: photographs of San Diego. 1935-1936 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Globe Theatre: programs from Chicago. 1934 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Globe Theatre: programs from San Diego. 1935-1936 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Globe Theatre: programs from Dallas. 1936 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Globe Theatre: programs from road trips. 1934-1937 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Globe Theatre: publicity in Chicago. 1934 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Globe Theatre: "Merrie England" at the World's Fair, New York. 1939 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Globe Theatre: schedules, financial reports, contracts, casts, etc. (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Globe Theatre: Shakespeare texts (Globe Theatre versions edited by Thomas Wood Stevens). (Box 23, Folder 11)
    All's Well That Ends Well
    As You Like It
    Comedy of Errors
    Hamlet
    Julius Caesar
    King Lear
    The Life and Death of Sir John Falstaff (typescript)
    Macbeth
    Midsummer Night's Dream
    Romeo and Juliet
    Taming of the Shrew
    Tempest
    Twelfth Night
  - Globe Theatre: commemorative programs. (Box 23, Folder 12)
    400th Anniversary of the birth of Shakespeare, 1964: Old Globe Theatre Program, San Diego.
    Ground-breaking of the new Old Globe Theatre (destroyed by fire) Saturday, December 1, 1979: Program, San Diego
  - Globe Theatre: notebook, cast plots for Globe Players; also original drawings for the poem Dark Discipline by Thomas Wood Stevens. (Box 23)
  - Globe Theatre: original watercolor of Globe stage by Thomas Wood Stevens. (Box 23)
  - Globe Theatre: scrapbook possibly compiled by Thomas Wood Stevens' sister. 1934-1936 (Box 23)
  - Globe Theatre: scrapbook compiled by John A. Willard, member of the Globe Players (Chicago, San Diego and road tours). 1934-1935 (Box 24)
  - Globe Theatre: scrapbook compiled by John A. Willard, member of the Globe Players (San Diego, Dallas and road tours). 1935-1937 (Box 25)
  - Globe Theatre: scrapbook compiled by John A. Willard, member of the Globe Players (Chicago, San Diego, Dallas and road tours). 1934-1937 (Box 26)
- Series II: Correspondence (continued), 1899-1942
  - General. 1935-1942 (Box 27, Folder 1-7)
    1941-1942 includes University of Arizona. See also Box 29 for programs, clippings, photographs.
  - Stanford University. (See also Box 29 for programs, clippings, photographs). 1937-1939 (Box 27, Folder 8-10)
  - National Theatre Conference. 1935, 1937 (Box 27, Folder 11-12)
  - Main Line Playhouse, Philadelphia. 1940-1941 (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - "Shakespeare in Action," "Folger Plan," etc. 1934, 1939 (Box 27, Folder 14)
- Series IV: Theater Materials (continued), 1901-1979
  - University and Community Theaters: miscellaneous and various groups. 1915-1932 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - University and Community Theaters: Chicago. 1901-1927 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - University and Community Theaters: New York City. 1915-1934 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    Includes Washington Square Players, Civic Repertory Players, Yvette Guilbert's School of the Theatre, etc.
  - University and Community Theaters: Garden Theatre, St. Louis (includes correspondence). Summers, 1926-1927 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - University and Community Theaters: Little Theatre of St. Louis. (See Box 21 for correspondence). 1931-1933 (Box 28, Folder 5-6)
  - University and Community Theaters: The Anatomist, London, directed by Thomas Wood Stevens. 1932 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - University and Community Theaters: Venus and Adolphus, by Thomas Wood Stevens. Produced at the Cleveland Playhouse, (includes correspondence). October 1939 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - University and Community Theaters: programs of Thomas Wood Stevens' plays produce by various groups. (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - University and Community Theaters: theatre periodicals (miscellaneous numbers). (Box 28, Folder 10)
    The Players, Bush Tempe Theatre, Chicago, December 18, 1905; October 22, 1906
    The Little Theatre Review, New York, vol. 1, no. 2, 6-7, 9, 1920-1921
    Little Theatres, New York Drama League, 1922-1923
    The Player, Detroit, Michigan, October 31, December 5, 1930
    The Show Bill, Biltmore Theatre, New York, vol. 1, no. 1, March 14, 1936
    Quarterly Bulletin, National Theatre Conference, vol. 2, no. 1, April 1940
  - University and Community Theaters: University of Michigan. (See Box 21 for correspondence). Summers, 1931-1933 (Box 29, Folder 1-3)
  - University and Community Theaters: Bonstelle Civic Theatre, Detroit. (See Box 21 for correspondence). 1933-1934 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - University and Community Theaters: Stanford University. (See Box 27 for correspondence). 1937-1939 (Box 29, Folder 5-6)
  - University and Community Theaters: University of Iowa. Summers, 1937, 1940-1941 (Box 29, Folder 7-8)
  - University and Community Theaters: University of Arizona. (See Box 27, Folder 7, for correspondence). 1941-1942 (Box 29, Folder 9)
- Series V: Pageants, 1900-1941